Bayazid Malikov

PERSONAL DETAILS

83/88, Alekperov, Binagadi Baku, Azerbaijan M: 055 821 4369 E: ml.bayazid@gmail.com Nationality: Azerbaijan Birth date: 10.02.1991

PERSONAL SUMMARY

As an MSc Finance graduate from the Manchester Business School with BSc in Economics from Qafqaz University and strong mathematical background my interests as well as my motivation lie in financial analysis. Having about two years of experience in corporate finance and accounting and solid educational background in economics and finance, I look forward to work in a market-leading company and apply my knowledge, experience and most importantly enthusiasm.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Position held & Dates Main activities and responsibilities

Financial Analyst: May 2013 - October 2013

- Forecasting, preparing and updating Cash Flow Statement. Reviewing the monthly financial performance and providing variance analysis and other commentary as appropriate.
- Prepare and report weekly/monthly company performance dashboards to Finance Manager and CEO. Assemble spreadsheets and draw charts and graphs to illustrate financial reports.
- Calculate and set Prices for goods on 1C System.
- Provide direct support to Finance Director and CFO.

"AzTexnika" LLC (construction machinery distributor), 15th km of Shamakhi road, Baku, Azerbaijan

Name and address of employer

Position held & Dates Main activities and responsibilities

Sales/Receivables Accountant: May 2012 - May 2013

- Preparation of Invoices for goods sold and services supplied.
- Update the Sales and Receivables Record daily according to the sales and payment receipts.
- Reconcile customer statements and correct discrepancies as necessary.
- Supply Management with the Overview of Receivables and assist in month-end financial statement close.
- Participated in the preparation of new map for internal documentation process.
- Check the company records and real-time data for fraud, money mismanagement and waste.

"AzTexnika" LLC (construction machinery distributor), 15th km of Shamakhi road, Baku, Azerbaijan

Name and address of employer

Position held & Dates Main activities and responsibilities

Name and address of employer

Position held & Dates Main activities and responsibilities

Name and address of employer

Internship: June-July 2011

Internship: July-August 2011

Contacting potential clients (companies and certain persons) and advertising business and consumer credits. Meeting up with clients and offering or giving credits in places.

Performing human resources assistant work; collecting, organizing, and reviewing data concerning employees. Checking, updating and reorganizing the employee database. "Azerinsaatservis LLC" (construction), Narimanov r., Ahmad Rajabli str. 50. Baku, Azerbaijan

"Bank of Baku" (banking), Ataturk Avenue 42. Baku, Azerbaijan

EDUCATION

Dates

2013-2014

Title of qualification awarded Name and type of organisation

Dates

Title of qualification awarded Name and type of organisation

MSc Finance (Dissertation- "Momentum Strategy and Analyst Based Valuation Methods") Manchester Business School, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK

2008-2013 (instruction language - English)

BSc Economics Qafqaz University, Baku, Azerbaijan

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Mother tongue Other languages **English** Russian **Turkish**

Azerbaijani

Native or bilingual proficiency Professional working proficiency Professional working proficiency

Page 1/2 - Curriculum vitae of Bayazid Malikov

Contact Details: Mobile: 055 821 4369 https://www.linkedin.com/pub/bayazid-malikov/33/b64/b44

E-Mail: ml.bayazid@gmail.com bayazid.malikov@postgrad.mbs.ac.uk

Computer skills and competences

- Excellent command of Microsoft Office tools (Word, Excel, PowerPoint etc.);
- Good command of :
 - ✓ 1C (v8)-Accounting (Enterprise Resource Planning software),
 - ✓ **SAP (FICO)** (Enterprise Resource Planning software),
 - ✓ Barraone (Risk management software),
 - ✓ **Eviews** (Econometric analysis software).
 - ✓ **Stata** (Data analysis and statistical software).
 - ✓ **SAS** (Statistical Analysis System),
 - ✓ Bloomberg Terminal (Real-time market data analysis).
- Basic knowledge of :
 - ✓ MATLAB (numerical computing and programming language),
 - Python (programming language).
- Basic knowledge of graphic design applications (Photoshop, 3D max, Z-brush).

Other skills and competences

- Multiple certificates in Mathematics and Logic,
- Have good drawing skills, professional chess player.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Personal Interests & Future Plans

- Drawing and Sculpting. Visiting Art galleries and museums. Love to travel, trade and experience different cultures. Enjoy all sports, particularly basketball and horseback riding. Follow financial and economic developments through multiple magazines and websites.
- Preparing for CIPM (Certificate in Investment Performance Measurement) program under CFA Institute.
- Working on a development of a new ERP software for the local businesses.

Researches & Projects & Trainings

- Participant of ongoing online courses in **Computational Investing** lectured by the professors of **Georgia Institute of Technology**,
- Empirical Research: "Timing as a Determinant of Abnormal Stock Returns Upon Equity Offering Announcements", Manchester University, 2014,
- Empirical Research: "Predicting Power of Narratives after 2008 Financial Crisis", Manchester University, 2014,
- Have participated in **social-economic research held by World Bank Group in 2012** which was related to development of Baku city,
- Participated in Qafqaz Business Forum and **won second place** with my team in business case competition held in Qafqaz University in 2012,
- Have participated in "III Math Logic Competition" as organizer and was awarded with a diploma,
- Participated at Azerbaijan Business Case Competition (ABCC) Trainings held by American Azerbaijan Alumni (AAA) organization,
- Participant of online courses in **Financial Modelling and Risk Management** lectured by the professors of **Columbia University**,
- Participant of online courses in **Mathematical Methods for Quantitative Finance** lectured by the professors of **Washington University**.

Awards & Certificates

- Full government sponsorship to study MSc Finance in the University of Manchester 2013-2014.
- IELTS(International English Language Testing System) score of 8.0 out of 9.0 in January, 2013,
- Diploma for high results in the "I Ideal Logic Competition" conducted by "Kainat" education centre in 2011.
- Diploma for being among the best students in the "I Math-Logic Competition" held by Qafqaz University in 2008,
- Full scholarship from Azerbaijan government for high undergraduate government examination (TQDK) score of 615/700 in 2008.

REFERENCES

Available on request.

https://www.linkedin.com/pub/bayazid-malikov/33/b64/b44
E-Mail: ml.bayazid@gmail.com bayazid.malikov@postgrad.mbs.ac.uk